Time to talk about something big.
Introducing Perks.
This is the most significant innovation to core gameplay
since Overwatch launched in 2016.
This is more than just an update.
It's a radical shift in how you experience gameplay.
Perks are upgrades to your hero's kit that unlock during the game.
They provide an additional strategic layer,
allowing you to alter your playstyle and adapt to situations.
Throughout the match,
you'll level up your hero two times,
unlocking one minor perk and one major perk.
The first time you level up,
you'll get a choice between two minor perks.
We positioned minor perks as lighter upgrades.
They're like a little boost to warm you up,
from cooldown reductions to small passives
that keep things balanced but exciting.
Once you hit your major perk level,
you'll get to choose between two powerful upgrades.
Then you fine-tune your playstyle for the rest of the match.
Major perks are gameplay-shifting additions to your hero's kit,
changing your core loop and redefining what your hero is capable of.
Let's look at an example now with Orisa.
When you level up Orisa to level two,
your minor perk choice will be between heat reduction on your primary
fire or the ability to briefly tank burst damage with Fortify.
Are you facing down a Junkrat and
want to be able to survive his tire?
The upgrade to Fortify might be a great choice.
The fun really gets going when you
get to your major perk at level three,
though.
Here, Orisa gets the choice between
a higher impact energy javelin or swapping
out her javelin spin for a protective barrier.
Here's another example of what you can
expect with major perks with Torbjorn.
For Torb's major perk options,
you get to choose between two wild upgrades for your turret.
The first perk option is allowing you to upgrade
your turret to level three when activating Overload,
drastically shifting your turret's
threat level as it rips through enemies.
The second perk option is if you're feeling
a little cheeky,
upgrading your turret to now stick on walls.
With this added flexibility,
Torbjorn can take different angles and even
surprise opponents with sneaky turret placement.
Finally,
let's round it out with Ana. Ana's first major perk
choice upgrades her sharpshooting capabilities,
allowing her to headshot enemies.
Be careful, Widowmaker.
You might lose this sniper duel.
Then,
if you're playing Ana and having a hard time getting Dovon,
you might want Ana's second
major perk option.
Give yourself nano boost when it's activated on an ally.
Now that's a way to turn a fight.
When designing perks,
we wanted to expand and elevate what your heroes are capable of.
We are looking for a system that we can layer on top of your
normal Overwatch gameplay and offer choice from match to match.
We plan on adjusting perks on a regular cadence with bigger
system refreshes happening in the middle of the year.
The choice you make with perks will impact the battlefield,
offering new opportunities to outplay enemies and support your team.
You'll get to experience the next era
of Overwatch 2 when Season 15 launches.